Cody Hillyard

Senior Software Developer with over 7 years of developing fully functional and profiting web solutions. Developing software systems and websites for ecommerce sites and SaaS applications using the latest techniques and technologies.

West Jordan, UT 84084 (435) 232-5941 codyhillyard@gmail.com codyhillyard.com

EXPERIENCE

SureFoot, Park City, Ut — *Software Developer & Devops*

2017 - 2018

Technologies used Linux, Apache, MySql, PHP, JavaScript, GIT, and Internal File Networking and Dev-ops utilities.

Enacted new version control system for Admin site complete with an active server administering multiple GIT repositories.

Upgraded all website code base from PHP 5.4 to 7.1

Integrated new libraries and deprecated code to latest deployments.

Added new server level backup systems and processes.

Monitored over the international printing and point of sale reporting and processing.

Advised on technical decisions for international store management.

Plansource, Salt Lake City, Ut — Senior Software Developer

2014 - 2017

Technologies used Linux, Ruby on Rails, MySql, JavaScript, Java, Capistrano, GIT, AWS, and Internal File Networking

Worked with many user interfaces and developed many html/css/javascript objects and frameworks for the user experience.

Interacted with internal and external customers to develop tools for improving and securing a benefit management reporting system.

Maintained the full life cycle of deployment including unit-testing, background processing and resource monitoring.

Created features and email data structures that integrated with the customer interaction system.

Worked with many deployment processes that would securely deploy code to the production servers.

Identified and fixed issues with the logging and validation systems by adjusting SQL and Object Oriented Classes.

WakeUpNow, Orem, Ut — Senior Software Developer

2013 - 2014

Technologies used Linux, Apache, MySql, PHP, JavaScript, AWS, GIT, and Internal File Networking

Maintained a fully functional Linux, Apache, MySql, and PHP system for an ecommerce MLM business.

Created user interface for processing payments, purchasing items and develop transitions to third party sites.

Developed a brand new permission feature system using Object Oriented PHP

SKILLS

PHP (CodeIgniter, Symfony, Wordpress)

Java (JSP, Swing, NodeJS applications)

Ruby (Rails 5+ and Gemset)

HTML5 and CSS functionality

SQL optimizing with various Database structures

AWS interfacing with multiple servers and load balancers

ReactJS integrations

Jenkins and Unit testing management

Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS, Redhat)

Apache setup and maintenance

Compliance Testing and QA management

Javascript (Node, Jquery, Backbone JS)

Capistrano Deployment

Asset pipeline management

development.

Created an interface for payment processing using dynamic structuring.

Created interfacing for secure log-in and storefront processing.

Connected a new process to manage hotel software handshakes though API's.

LenovoEMC, Roy, Ut — Database Administrator

2012 - 2013

Technologies used Linux, Apache, MySql, PHP, AWS, JavaScript, Subversion, and Internal File Networking

Design, code and implement a Return Item Portal to manage reporting for LenovoEMC Inventory Worldwide.

Created all user interfaces for the portal with new account interfaces.

Using Object Oriented Design created validation and connections to existing data objects from multiple sources to display in one page.

Funium LLC, Lehi, Ut — Scrum Master

2010 - 2012

Technologies used Linux, Apache, MySql, PHP, Wordpress, AWS, JavaScript, Subversion, Internal File Networking, ActionScript, and Facebook API interfacing.

Created Scrum Master position that had oversight of the Development, Artistic and Design departments.

Created deployment process for AWS interface that would maintain multiple servers and a load balancer.

Developed in game process management system using nodejs as the server.

Created web pages for Facebook game to interact with our servers and Facebook API.

Moore BCS, Logan, Ut — Weekend Team Lead

Over 8 years of service

Technologies used Motherboards, A+ Maintenance, Windows, Word, Excel

Work for Over 8 years in the direct mailing department.

Went from temporary worker to Team Lead for the Weekend shift.

Ran Inserting machines that could $\,$ produce over 5000 stuffed and processed mail pieces per hour.

EDUCATION

Utah State University, Logan, Ut — BS in Computer Science

Digital Systems Major with Engineering emphasis

Manzanola High School, Manzanola, Co — High School Diploma